<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:15:44 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Holy Roman Empire : A Thousand Years of Europe&#39;s History</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-holy-roman-empire-peter-h-wilson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2018 05:15:44 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-holy-roman-empire-peter-h-wilson/</guid>
      <description>The Holy Roman Empire is a confusing concept. As Voltaire once put it, the empire was neither &amp;ldquo;holy, nor Roman, nor an empire,&amp;rdquo; and that was indeed true at the time of Voltaire, as the medieval empire had grown into something that, by the early modern period, resembled nothing we understand as a &amp;ldquo;country&amp;rdquo; or a &amp;ldquo;nation&amp;rdquo; today. While predominantly an empire of German people, as its later name, Heiliges Römisches Reich Deutscher Nation (albeit not an oft-used name), suggests, it is in fact a collection of people who we would regard today as &amp;ldquo;Germans&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Franks, Bavarians, Saxons, etc&amp;mdash;and those who we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t regard as &amp;ldquo;Germans&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;Austrians, Swiss, Dutch, Poles, Bohemians, northern Italians, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austerlitz</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/austerlitz-wg-sebald/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 17:54:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/austerlitz-wg-sebald/</guid>
      <description>In the run up to the Second World War, Britain took on about ten thousands of Jewish children in a rescue effort now known as Kindertransport. These children came from areas already or soon-to-be occupied by Nazi Germany, and they were brought up in Great Britain by foster parents. Jacques Austerlitz, who arrived in England at an age so young that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have remembered much about his former life, and whose Welsh foster parents concealed his true identity for long enough to erase any last memory of his prior existence, put off attempting to find his root until he had become an old man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second-Hand Time</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/second-hand-time-svetlana-alexievich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 04:03:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/second-hand-time-svetlana-alexievich/</guid>
      <description>It would have been a strange situation to find yourself in, that the ideas you&amp;rsquo;d grown up with turned out to be out-of-fashion, and that what you&amp;rsquo;d been working for your whole life turned out to be worthless. It happens every so often to some people, but rarely at the scale of a whole country.
In her latest work, Svetlana Alexievich, the winner of Nobel Prize in 2015, tackles exactly this strange phenomenon during the collapse and the aftermath of the collapse of the Soviet Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices from Chernobyl: The Oral History of a Nuclear Disaster</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/voices-from-chernobyl-svetlana-alexievich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 16:34:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/voices-from-chernobyl-svetlana-alexievich/</guid>
      <description>Some years ago, I went through a phase of watching every documentary film I could get my hands on. One of the films I stumbled upon was a film about the Chernobyl disaster. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember when I first watched it, and it might not have anything to do with the Fukushima disaster. As with so many of the things I find interesting, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any inherent reason why I found the Chernobyl disaster fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War and Peace</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/war-and-peace-leo-tolstoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 02:40:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/war-and-peace-leo-tolstoy/</guid>
      <description>It is difficult to pin down what &amp;ldquo;War and Peace&amp;rdquo; exactly is. In large part, it tells the stories of several Russian aristocratic families&amp;mdash;the Rostovs, Bolkonskys, the Bezhukovs, and others&amp;mdash;with great realism, against the backdrop of the Napoleonic Wars, starting roughly from the time of the Battle of Austerlitz to the defeat of Napoleon by the Russians. Just as his later novel, &amp;ldquo;Anna Karenina, &amp;ldquo;War and Peace&amp;rdquo; embraces everything possible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>