<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Loss on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/loss/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Loss on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 14:02:39 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/loss/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Sister</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/my-sister/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 14:02:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/my-sister/</guid>
      <description>I last saw my sister, Kate, about five years ago. Since that day, neither me, our parents, nor our friends had heard anything from her or about her. Back when her disappearance was still fresh on everyone&amp;rsquo;s mind, everyone I knew offering help, both tangible and emotional, to me and to my parents; but soon, the memories of her faded from people&amp;rsquo;s mind like words on an old piece of paper, and they move on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coffee Shop</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-coffee-shop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 17:34:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-coffee-shop/</guid>
      <description>A bustling crowd gathered in a coffee shop. On weekdays, customers came to this busy spot in the busiest street of the city centre to get their drinks and left in a hurry, but on this slow, summer, Saturday afternoon, many stayed with their company, enjoying their iced beverages and snacks. Simon, who wore a light blue shirt and grey suit jacket despite the day&amp;rsquo;s being a day-off, was the only customer without any of his friends around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorrow in the Dark</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/sorrow-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 05:48:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/sorrow-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>The night is always when the sorrow grows:
The world is silent, everyone&amp;rsquo;s asleep.
I sit alone and let my sadness flows,
My eyes run dry despite my urge to weep.
Your kindness gives me courage to survive,
Your caring touches me and warms my heart.
But all your words and words cannot revive
The sense of life that has been ripped apart.
The lights of city mask the twinkling stars,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He who does not forget</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/he-who-does-not-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 13:00:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/he-who-does-not-forget/</guid>
      <description>An old photo is hung on the wall. It is his first wife, Anita, staring at him from the wall since he divorced his second wife. Other than some slight yellowish discolourations, Anita looks exactly as he still remembers: long dark hair, bright eyes, and a smile that showed the dental braces.
Andrew didn&amp;rsquo;t understand why he wanted to fetch that picture, along with other things, from a storage space he rented just outside of the downtown, though it certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t to remind him of her face, because he couldn&amp;rsquo;t, and still can&amp;rsquo;t, forget anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My life did not go on</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/my-life-did-not-go-on/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 19:25:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/my-life-did-not-go-on/</guid>
      <description>After you left me,
They said life would go on.
But my life did not go on,
As it became&amp;mdash;
My life minus you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I waited for your call</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-waited-for-your-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:05:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-waited-for-your-call/</guid>
      <description>I watched my phone and waited for your call
But never heard from you nor seen your trace.
The endless waiting made my anguish tall,
My heart was pumping fast like running race.
The wine had not my poor nerve calmed the least,
The music roused my soul with bitter rage.
I closed my eyes and wished my pain decreased,
The storm in me was trapped within a cage.
My tears were falling through the stale sad air,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think about you to dream of you</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-think-about-you-to-dream-of-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 18:44:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-think-about-you-to-dream-of-you/</guid>
      <description>They used to say: &amp;ldquo;you dream of what you think.&amp;rdquo;
So I thought about you to dream of you,
I poured a glass of bitter wine to drink
Myself to sleep the sleep and dream of you.
But then I looked and searched and found you not,
Instead I heard her voice and saw her face.
She said her love for me had yet to rot,
But in truth, it&amp;rsquo;s long gone to outer space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We were all once young and dumb</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/we-were-all-once-young-and-dumb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 16:52:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/we-were-all-once-young-and-dumb/</guid>
      <description>I sat and thought about the distant past
When we were all once young and very dumb.
I gave you up for love which hardly last:
The love which broke my heart; regrets to come.
I needed you to heal my wounded soul,
But you were hurt as much and left the place.
I looked for you with my heart hardly whole,
With tears flow like little streams on my face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You are the antidote to my pain</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/you-antidote-pain-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/you-antidote-pain-love/</guid>
      <description>I gave you my love, you gave me poison,
The only antidote of which was you.
You left me alone, my heart was frozen,
My eyes shed blood as I died without you.
Originally posted on Medium</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was the lone passenger, until…</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/lone-passenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/lone-passenger/</guid>
      <description>Alone on a quiet, frozen train, I rode
With no one but the sound of speeding wheels.
Approaching the next station, the train slowed.
There, she announced her entrance with her heels.
I turned towards the new presence, who sat
With her face towards me. She was alone.
She smiled at me. My heart shuddered at that,
For she was both a known and an unknown —
She had to be a twin sister of yours</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Music</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/forgotten-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/forgotten-music/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, when I was tidying up my study, I flipped open the score of Chopin’s Mazurkas, and I discovered that the pages for one of the Mazurkas was filled with pencil markings, a clear indication that I had learned that piece at one point, yet I couldn’t remember having learned it at all. I took it to the piano, and as I played it for the first time in decades, my fingers seemed to run on the keyboard on their own to the right directions and hit the right keys, an indisputable proof that I had learned the piece at some point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Eraser</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/memory-eraser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/memory-eraser/</guid>
      <description>It was the year twenty-two hundred.
You wished to forget everything that happened to you in the past five years, so you went to a hospital and demanded the mixture of drugs — advertised somewhere — that could erase your memory.
When you saw the doctor, he was reluctant to erase your memory straight away. He asked you tonnes of questions that annoyed you, and in the end, he said: “You will regret that, I know you will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face, Without Glasses</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/face-without-glasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/face-without-glasses/</guid>
      <description>I have been wearing glasses since I was a kid, so I have always remembered myself having a pair of glasses on my face: my only memory of my face. The only times I can see myself not wearing glasses are those occasions when I look into the mirror while washing my face or something. But since my short-sightedness is serious, I can only see the image in the mirror clearly when I get very close to the mirror, which means I can only see a very small portion of my face in the mirror when I am not wearing my glasses.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>