<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Caddy on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Caddy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Caddy on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 13:34:24 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Caddy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Serve static websites with Caddy web server</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/caddy-webserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 13:34:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/caddy-webserver/</guid>
      <description>First, a little bit of history.
I have been running websites&amp;mdash;personal or otherwise&amp;mdash;on-and-off for long enough to remember Geocities. Although I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t claim to be an expert, I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and done quite a bit over the years, from hand-coding HTML files and uploading files via FTP to running Wordpress on LAMP and LEMP stacks and experimenting with Varnish Cache.
I stopped making websites for a while before building this website with static site generators (first with Jekyll, then with Hugo).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I deploy my Hugo site to my webserver</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-site-deployment-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 16:42:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-site-deployment-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This post has been updated to reflect my new deployment process after migrating to Firebase This post has been updated to reflect further important changes
Static site generators are great&amp;mdash;Jekyll is great, and Hugo is even greater&amp;mdash;except when it comes to updating the website. In the old days of my using wordpress, updating a post was a matter of logging in to the Wordpress Admin, making changes to the post, and hitting the &amp;ldquo;save&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
