<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Art on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Art on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 10:30:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosaline</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/rosaline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 10:30:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/rosaline/</guid>
      <description>Her father named her Rosaline, a beautiful name. But he hated her, because she killed her mother.
&amp;ldquo;Little Frank wasn&amp;rsquo;t like that,&amp;rdquo; her grandmother would tell her much later. &amp;ldquo;After your mother died while giving birth to you, my little Frank began drinking. He drank away his fortune, his everything&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
When he was drunk, he would beat her for no real reasons. Once she used a few crayons she got from her art lessons to draw something on a wall in the living room while he was not at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On musical structure and storytelling</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-musical-structure-and-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 11:30:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-musical-structure-and-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent much of my early life trying to be a classical musician&amp;mdash;a pianist, or a conductor, perhaps&amp;mdash;before spending a lot of time thinking of becoming a writer and actually doing something about it. So it may sound strange to you, but I often think of fiction in musical terms. A novel is a symphony, while a short story is a short piano piece by Chopin.
As someone who loves orchestral music more than piano music, let me say from the outset that I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of Chopin&amp;rsquo;s music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On happy endings</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-happy-endings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 03:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-happy-endings/</guid>
      <description>Christian Thielemann, one of the best, if not the best, conductors of the works of Wagner alive, once noted that none of the Wagner operas end in minor keys. Indeed, not even the apocalyptic ending of Götterdämmerung, the fourth and the final installment of the epic cycle Der Ring des Nibelungen, where the world ends with Brünnhilde jumping into the fire and the gods dies, ends in a minor key: Der Ring des Nibelungen starts with Das Rheingold in E-flat major and ends with Götterdämmerung in D-flat major.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>