<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fiction on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Fiction on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 04:07:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Man in Love - My Struggle 2</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/my-struggle-2-karl-ove-knausgaard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 04:07:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/my-struggle-2-karl-ove-knausgaard/</guid>
      <description>Somewhere in the middle of the book, Karl Ove Knausgaard spends some twenty or so pages describing the day his wife gave birth to his first daughter, and those pages mostly are about her wife&amp;rsquo;s screaming her head off in pain every half an hour or so.
In this series of books, it does appear that Karl Ove Knausgaard has pulled of something writers and readers alike think is impossible, which is to write something so incredibly boring and not put readers off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Death in the Family</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/my-struggle-1-karl-ove-knausgaard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 04:07:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/my-struggle-1-karl-ove-knausgaard/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death&#39;s End</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/deaths-end-cixin-liu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 May 2017 21:02:16 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/deaths-end-cixin-liu/</guid>
      <description>In some ways, this is perhaps the weakest book of the trilogy, in part because the scope has expanded to such an extent to include not just the Trisolarans, but also space species of other origins, the time span of the story stretches to centuries-long, and the speculative aspect of science outside of relativity and quantum mechanics is pushed so far beyond what seems possible, that the story verges on the level of absurdity on par with some episodes of Doctor Who.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dark Forest</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-dark-forest-cixin-liu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 02:59:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-dark-forest-cixin-liu/</guid>
      <description>Following the events of The Three-Body Problem and facing the impending arrival of the Trisolaran&amp;rsquo;s invasion fleet in four centuries, humanity has plunged into some kind of chaos. As in all alien invasions in fiction, the extraterrestrial beings have a fatal flaw ready to be exploited by human beings, and it is the job of the four Wallfacers, appointed by the United Nation, to plot against the Trisolarans.
In a story that spans more than two centuries, with the Trisolarans having travelled some two lightyears, battles taking place at the edge of our solar system, and humanity living through anxiety, despair, hope, apathy, and victory (or is it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three-Body Problem</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-three-body-problem-cixin-liu/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 02:59:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-three-body-problem-cixin-liu/</guid>
      <description>A science fiction masterpiece, The Three-Body Problem is an imaginative story dealing with human&amp;rsquo;s communication with and the potential destruction by a hypothetical alien race from our nearest star system, Alpha Centauri, which is a three-star system (hence the name of the book).
With a scope even greater than Star Wars, The Three-Body Problem is a spectacle in itself, but it is also a setup for the next book in the series, The Dark Forest, which takes the scope of the narrative to the next level and asks some serious questions for readers to ponder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Longest Distance</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-longest-distance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2016 18:54:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-longest-distance/</guid>
      <description>All that remained was the date of her birthday according to the solar calendar of Alte Welt. Since Sophie left him for another man, Ethan had moved to Neue Welt, where each year was twenty days shorter and each day was twenty minutes longer. After just few Neue Welt days, he could no longer convert dates and times from the Alte Welt clock to the new one, and vice versa. It wasn’t until when he heard the video message from an old friend Jimmy&amp;ndash;with a twenty minutes delay in transmission (anything resembling a phone call between Alte Welt and Neue Welt was impossible)&amp;ndash;that another of his good friend in Alte Welt died did he attempt to figure out what day it was back there, a task he failed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Man in the High Castle</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-man-in-the-high-castle-philip-k-dick/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 13:44:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-man-in-the-high-castle-philip-k-dick/</guid>
      <description>Nazi Germany and Imperial Japan had won the Second World War, and the United States was partitioned by Germany and Japan. White people were no longer the privileged ones (not in Japan-occupied zone), Jews had all but vanished from New York, and Herbert von Karajan became the Chief Conductor of the New York Philharmonic. In that alternative world, a book about an alternative history where the Allies won the war captured the imagination of the oppressed, while the oppressor sought to murder the person who wrote that book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Austerlitz</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/austerlitz-wg-sebald/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2016 17:54:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/austerlitz-wg-sebald/</guid>
      <description>In the run up to the Second World War, Britain took on about ten thousands of Jewish children in a rescue effort now known as Kindertransport. These children came from areas already or soon-to-be occupied by Nazi Germany, and they were brought up in Great Britain by foster parents. Jacques Austerlitz, who arrived in England at an age so young that he couldn&amp;rsquo;t have remembered much about his former life, and whose Welsh foster parents concealed his true identity for long enough to erase any last memory of his prior existence, put off attempting to find his root until he had become an old man.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cologne</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/misc/cologne-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 17:11:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/misc/cologne-germany/</guid>
      <description>Cologne, or Köln, always makes me think of what Marcel Proust wrote about Combray in The Way by Swann’s:
 Combray, from far away, for ten leagues around, seen from the railroad when we arrived there the last week before Easter, was no more than a church summing up the town, representing it, speaking of it and for it into the distance, and, when one approached, holding close around its high dark cloak, in the middle of a field, against the wing, like a shepherdess her sheep, the woolly grey backs of the gathered houses, which a vestige of medieval ramparts girdled here and there with a line as perfectly circular as a small town in a primitive painting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Coffee Shop</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-coffee-shop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2016 17:34:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-coffee-shop/</guid>
      <description>A bustling crowd gathered in a coffee shop. On weekdays, customers came to this busy spot in the busiest street of the city centre to get their drinks and left in a hurry, but on this slow, summer, Saturday afternoon, many stayed with their company, enjoying their iced beverages and snacks. Simon, who wore a light blue shirt and grey suit jacket despite the day&amp;rsquo;s being a day-off, was the only customer without any of his friends around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love in the Time of Cholera</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/love-in-the-time-of-cholera-gabriel-garcia-marquez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2016 03:58:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/love-in-the-time-of-cholera-gabriel-garcia-marquez/</guid>
      <description>Without one single wasted word, Gabriel García Márquez told a story about love in its many guises, from the youthful, passionate love, lust, to the love in old people.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Heart of Darkness</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/heart-of-darkness-joseph-conrad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jul 2016 16:16:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/heart-of-darkness-joseph-conrad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operas and Their Absurd Stories</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-operas-and-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 06:46:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-operas-and-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>Natalie Dessay, a French soprano, once said that text of many operas are silly. She wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first to say it, and she won&amp;rsquo;t be the last.
Mozart&amp;rsquo;s Die Zauberflöte, the libretto of which was written by Emmanuel Schikaneder, is a great first-time opera: it has tuneful melodies, humours, and relatively easy story. But when you strip away the Masonic theme, Die Zauberflöte is a love story that makes no sense: Tamino falls in love with Pamina because he sees her picture, and Pamina falls in love with Tamino because she hears that Tamino falls in love with her after seeing her picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosaline</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/rosaline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 10:30:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/rosaline/</guid>
      <description>Her father named her Rosaline, a beautiful name. But he hated her, because she killed her mother.
&amp;ldquo;Little Frank wasn&amp;rsquo;t like that,&amp;rdquo; her grandmother would tell her much later. &amp;ldquo;After your mother died while giving birth to you, my little Frank began drinking. He drank away his fortune, his everything&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;
When he was drunk, he would beat her for no real reasons. Once she used a few crayons she got from her art lessons to draw something on a wall in the living room while he was not at home.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Lady of the Camellias</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/la-dame-aus-camelias-alexandre-dumas-fils/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 17:20:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/la-dame-aus-camelias-alexandre-dumas-fils/</guid>
      <description>La Dame aux Camélias is the basis for one of the best known operas in the entire operatic repertoire: Giuseppe Verdi&amp;rsquo;s La Traviata.
Having known the opera and watched the Opéra de Paris&amp;rsquo; production of it at Opéra Bastille, I knew the story roughly before I read the novel, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect any surprise, nor did I anticipate being moved by it. After all, most stories in operas are quite quite weak, and the magic of operas are held more by the charm of singers, the spectacles, and the music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What We Talk About When We Talk About Love</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/what-we-talk-about-when-we-talk-about-love-raymond-carver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 May 2016 01:11:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/what-we-talk-about-when-we-talk-about-love-raymond-carver/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>He who does not forget</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/he-who-does-not-forget/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 13:00:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/he-who-does-not-forget/</guid>
      <description>An old photo is hung on the wall. It is his first wife, Anita, staring at him from the wall since he divorced his second wife. Other than some slight yellowish discolourations, Anita looks exactly as he still remembers: long dark hair, bright eyes, and a smile that showed the dental braces.
Andrew didn&amp;rsquo;t understand why he wanted to fetch that picture, along with other things, from a storage space he rented just outside of the downtown, though it certainly wasn&amp;rsquo;t to remind him of her face, because he couldn&amp;rsquo;t, and still can&amp;rsquo;t, forget anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Lost Time (Volume 3): The Guermantes Way</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/in-search-of-lost-time-iii-marcel-proust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 05:57:38 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/in-search-of-lost-time-iii-marcel-proust/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Lost Time (Volume 2): In the Shadow of Young Girls in Flower</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/in-search-of-lost-time-ii-marcel-proust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 05:57:37 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/in-search-of-lost-time-ii-marcel-proust/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Search of Lost Time (Volume 1): The Way by Swann&#39;s</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/in-search-of-lost-time-i-marcel-proust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 May 2016 05:57:36 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/in-search-of-lost-time-i-marcel-proust/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;In Search of Lost Time&amp;rdquo; is famous for, first of all, its length. With seven volumes (or six, as in this translation), it is among the longest novels ever written. &amp;ldquo;In Search of Lost Time&amp;rdquo; is also famous for its use of very long sentences. Consider the opening sentence of chapter 2 of part 1 of the first volume:
 Combray, from far away, for ten leagues around, seen from the railroad when we arrived there the last week before Easter, was no more than a church summing up the town, representing it, speaking of it and for it into the distance, and, when one approached, holding close around its high dark cloak, in the middle of a field, against the wind, like a shepherdess her sheep, the woolly grey backs of the gathered houses, which a vestige of medieval ramparts girdled here and there with a line as perfectly circular as a small town in a primitive painting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On musical structure and storytelling</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-musical-structure-and-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 11:30:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-musical-structure-and-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent much of my early life trying to be a classical musician&amp;mdash;a pianist, or a conductor, perhaps&amp;mdash;before spending a lot of time thinking of becoming a writer and actually doing something about it. So it may sound strange to you, but I often think of fiction in musical terms. A novel is a symphony, while a short story is a short piano piece by Chopin.
As someone who loves orchestral music more than piano music, let me say from the outset that I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of Chopin&amp;rsquo;s music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What you feel when you kill yourself</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/what-you-feel-when-you-kill-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 03:36:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/what-you-feel-when-you-kill-yourself/</guid>
      <description>I always wonder what you felt when you were in the process of killing yourself.
I sometimes picture myself jumping off a high building, stabbing myself in the heart, or taking a crazy amount of painkillers and strong alcohol together. When earth&amp;rsquo;s gravity pulls me down at 10ms-2, what will I feel when the wind came rushing towards my face? What will I feel when I hit the ground? How painful will that be?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to blow up the world</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/how-to-take-revenge-on-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/how-to-take-revenge-on-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Florian sat at his place in the open-planned office, staring at the grey screen, with colourful codes standing out against the dark screen. He was asked to fix a stupid bug in the operating system his employer sold to millions. Fixing bugs had ben his only job for a few years now.
This is so fucking boring. This job is just a glorified fire-fighter. In fact, even fire-fighter&amp;rsquo;s job is more glorious than mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On happy endings</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-happy-endings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 03:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-happy-endings/</guid>
      <description>Christian Thielemann, one of the best, if not the best, conductors of the works of Wagner alive, once noted that none of the Wagner operas end in minor keys. Indeed, not even the apocalyptic ending of Götterdämmerung, the fourth and the final installment of the epic cycle Der Ring des Nibelungen, where the world ends with Brünnhilde jumping into the fire and the gods dies, ends in a minor key: Der Ring des Nibelungen starts with Das Rheingold in E-flat major and ends with Götterdämmerung in D-flat major.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wrong Affair</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/wrong-affair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 09:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/wrong-affair/</guid>
      <description>The temperature was well above 34 degree centigrade under the summer sun. With tall buildings trapping the air, hundreds of people jamming into narrow pavements, and cars blowing out hot and toxic exhaust gasses, the streets at the heart of Hong Kong was a bamboo steamer in dim sum restaurants. Elizabeth Leung was wearing a white, short-sleeve top, but she regretted not wearing a skirt, which would allow some occasional breezes for her legs; not there those breezes would be cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hobbit &amp; The Lord of the Rings</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-hobbit-the-lord-of-the-rings-j-r-r-tolkien/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2016 17:28:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/the-hobbit-the-lord-of-the-rings-j-r-r-tolkien/</guid>
      <description>Let me begin by confessing that I am no big fan of J. R. R. Tolkien&amp;rsquo;s The Lord of the Rings cycle, and that makes me open to attacks from passionate fans of the cycle.
One of the problems I have with The Lord of the Rings is its similarities with another Ring cycle: Der Ring des Nibelungen by Richard Wagner. One reason for the similarities between two Ring cycles is that both Wagner and Tolkien appeared to have consult the same sources in Norse Mythology&amp;mdash;Völsunga saga and Nibelungenlied&amp;mdash;but it is hard to believe that Tolkien was entirely not influenced by Wagner&amp;rsquo;s Ring, even though he refused to admit it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gang Leader</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</guid>
      <description>“By some account, he was the richest person in the country.” The line came from the obituary of Super Man (Man was his last name), the gang leader who once terrorised the populace of the Republic of Slofland, and who later ripped money off the same populace. Towards the end of his life, he became wealthy and, as a result of his wealth, respectable.
When his mother read that line, she smiled with pride, as if the mere fact that her son was rich were more than enough to compensate for the fact that her son was dead before she became a corpse herself: he was only thirty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On reading Marcel Proust: Part 1</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/random-thoughts-on-marcel-proust-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/random-thoughts-on-marcel-proust-1/</guid>
      <description>The fault I find with our journalism is that it forces us to take an interest in some fresh triviality or other every day, whereas only three or four books in a lifetime give us anything that is of real importance.
 One of the writers who influences me a great deal is Marcel Proust. His never-ending In Search of Lost Time is such a monstrosity that there are places when even a great admirer like myself would wonder why did you write this?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Living Soul</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-last-living-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-last-living-soul/</guid>
      <description>I knew. For a long time, I knew I was in part a creation of someone called the scientist. Since the scientist was responsible for the existence of me and others of my own type, a few of us regarded the scientist with a god-like reverence, while others held him/her in utter contempt. No one knew him/her: there was no photograph, painted portrait, nor busts of the scientist, and we had no idea regarding his/her name, and whether this person was a man or woman.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Music</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/forgotten-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/forgotten-music/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, when I was tidying up my study, I flipped open the score of Chopin’s Mazurkas, and I discovered that the pages for one of the Mazurkas was filled with pencil markings, a clear indication that I had learned that piece at one point, yet I couldn’t remember having learned it at all. I took it to the piano, and as I played it for the first time in decades, my fingers seemed to run on the keyboard on their own to the right directions and hit the right keys, an indisputable proof that I had learned the piece at some point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Eraser</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/memory-eraser/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/memory-eraser/</guid>
      <description>It was the year twenty-two hundred.
You wished to forget everything that happened to you in the past five years, so you went to a hospital and demanded the mixture of drugs — advertised somewhere — that could erase your memory.
When you saw the doctor, he was reluctant to erase your memory straight away. He asked you tonnes of questions that annoyed you, and in the end, he said: “You will regret that, I know you will.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Face, Without Glasses</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/face-without-glasses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/face-without-glasses/</guid>
      <description>I have been wearing glasses since I was a kid, so I have always remembered myself having a pair of glasses on my face: my only memory of my face. The only times I can see myself not wearing glasses are those occasions when I look into the mirror while washing my face or something. But since my short-sightedness is serious, I can only see the image in the mirror clearly when I get very close to the mirror, which means I can only see a very small portion of my face in the mirror when I am not wearing my glasses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Swimmer From The Desert</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/a-swimmer-from-the-desert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/a-swimmer-from-the-desert/</guid>
      <description>For the sake of simplicity, we have always called him A, for we do not know what his actual name is (Akxhhhgg-something-something-something-something).
Neither do we know exactly where he came from, except the fact that his homeland was in the middle of a desert. When we met him for the first time in our town, thousands of miles away from his home, he could not speak our tongue at all, and for the first few days of our acquaintance with him, we could only point to things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>War and Peace</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/war-and-peace-leo-tolstoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 02:40:50 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/war-and-peace-leo-tolstoy/</guid>
      <description>It is difficult to pin down what &amp;ldquo;War and Peace&amp;rdquo; exactly is. In large part, it tells the stories of several Russian aristocratic families&amp;mdash;the Rostovs, Bolkonskys, the Bezhukovs, and others&amp;mdash;with great realism, against the backdrop of the Napoleonic Wars, starting roughly from the time of the Battle of Austerlitz to the defeat of Napoleon by the Russians. Just as his later novel, &amp;ldquo;Anna Karenina, &amp;ldquo;War and Peace&amp;rdquo; embraces everything possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anna Karenina</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/anna-karenina-leo-tolstoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 May 2015 02:39:58 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/anna-karenina-leo-tolstoy/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Anna Karenina&amp;rdquo; opens with one of the most iconic sentences in the whole of literature:
 All happy families are alike; each unhappy family is unhappy in its own way.
 The validity of this claim is even more questionable than the opening line of Jane Austen&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Pride and Prejudice&amp;rdquo;:
 It is a truth universally acknowledged, that a single man in possession of a good fortune, must be in want of a wife.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>