<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 15:29:12 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to show related posts in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/related-posts-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 15:29:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/related-posts-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>The ability to show related posts is not yet a feature in Hugo. At present, one way to achieve this is by showing posts that have common tags or categories with the intersect function, as described in Hugo&amp;rsquo;s documentation.
This, however, will list all the posts with at least one common tag for any given post, which isn&amp;rsquo;t what most people want. For a while, I have been using CSS to hide the list of related posts and only show the first three, a workaround suggested by Justin Dunham, a workaround that I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly like.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customising categories URLs in Hugo revisited</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/advanced-custom-urls-for-category-pages-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 13:06:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/advanced-custom-urls-for-category-pages-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>A while ago, I wrote a simple workaround for customising URLs of categories pages in Hugo. The purpose was to remove the word &amp;ldquo;categories&amp;rdquo; from the URLs of categories pages, a feature (still) missing in Hugo.
That workaround is simple, and it replicates the behaviour in my old Jekyll site, though it isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect: it can only generate one single page for each category without pagination, while the &amp;ldquo;original&amp;rdquo; categories pages supports pagination out of the box.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Github Pages to Firebase, then to a VPS</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/switching-from-github-pages-to-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 15:07:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/switching-from-github-pages-to-firebase/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I went static, I have been using Github Pages, an almost perfect solution for small static sites.
The only real shortcoming of Github Pages is the lack of control over the webserver, and hence the lack of control over caching and server-side redirect. While using Cloudflare does give you back some control, redirect capability remains lacking.
A few weeks ago, I moved the site to Firebase, which was a step up from Github Pages in terms of its flexibility, though I remained somewhat dissatisfied for various minor annoyances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Data Files in Hugo: an example</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-data-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 07:49:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-data-files/</guid>
      <description>In this article, I am going to demonstrate how to use Data Files in Hugo site generator.
The Problem As an effort to grow this website, I thought it might be a good idea to have a collection of interesting quotes by great novelists and writers. Even if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help traffic, it would still be beneficial for me as a writer.
An easy and obvious way to achieve this is to create a regular page and list all the quotes inside that page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I deploy my Hugo site to my webserver</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-site-deployment-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 16:42:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-site-deployment-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This post has been updated to reflect my new deployment process after migrating to Firebase This post has been updated to reflect further important changes
Static site generators are great&amp;mdash;Jekyll is great, and Hugo is even greater&amp;mdash;except when it comes to updating the website. In the old days of my using wordpress, updating a post was a matter of logging in to the Wordpress Admin, making changes to the post, and hitting the &amp;ldquo;save&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to customise categories and tags URLs in Hugo</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/custom-urls-for-category-pages-in-hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 13:45:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/custom-urls-for-category-pages-in-hugo/</guid>
      <description>Update: Here is a new advanced hack for customising categories URLs
Hugo is a great static site generator. Fast page build time and built-in live reload make Hugo a joy to use. But it isn&amp;rsquo;t without its limitation.
One of the limitations I touched upon is the lack of completely customisable taxonomies URLs. By default, categories are located in /categories/something, and tags are located in /tags/something. If you want to change the word &amp;ldquo;categories&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; in the URLs into some other words, there is a simple solution, as I explained on Github:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo vs. Jekyll: a showdown of static site generator</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-vs-jekyll-static-site-generator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 06:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-vs-jekyll-static-site-generator/</guid>
      <description>Last week, I mentioned that this site is built using Jekyll, a static site generator that, once you get used to it, is much faster to load and more convenient than dynamic content management system such as Wordpress.
(Update: this site now runs on Hugo)
Jekyll is way too slow Jekyll is a good alternative to things like Wordpress, but it isn&amp;rsquo;t without its own problem: the loading speed of the compiled static pages may be very fast because they are static, but those pages take a long time to build.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
