<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>City on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/City/</link>
    <description>Recent content in City on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 16:50:38 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/City/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Berlin</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/misc/berlin-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Aug 2016 16:50:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/misc/berlin-germany/</guid>
      <description>My earliest memory about Berlin wasn&amp;rsquo;t Berlin itself, but a Laser Disc of Herbert von Karajan conducting the Berliner Philharmoniker, performing Beethoven 6thsymphony. The way Karajan made music film was peculiar: all the musicians were lined up perfectly, all the bows and violins were aligned, all the flutes were tilted at the same angle, and so on. When they played, the body movements, other than the movements necessary to make some sound on their instruments, were minimal; in fact, they looked so rigid that it was as if Karajan were directing a team of robots.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cologne</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/misc/cologne-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 17:11:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/misc/cologne-germany/</guid>
      <description>Cologne, or Köln, always makes me think of what Marcel Proust wrote about Combray in The Way by Swann’s:
 Combray, from far away, for ten leagues around, seen from the railroad when we arrived there the last week before Easter, was no more than a church summing up the town, representing it, speaking of it and for it into the distance, and, when one approached, holding close around its high dark cloak, in the middle of a field, against the wing, like a shepherdess her sheep, the woolly grey backs of the gathered houses, which a vestige of medieval ramparts girdled here and there with a line as perfectly circular as a small town in a primitive painting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Munich</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/misc/munich-germany/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 17:10:31 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/misc/munich-germany/</guid>
      <description>I had bought the flight to München long before the trip, but other than a concert in München and another one in Berlin, I had no idea what places I would most want to visit. At the time I purchased my flight, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have foreseen the trip being of any significance to me, for it was supposed to be just another normal, purposeless two-week trip that would be filled with pointless sightseeing and even more pointless souvenirs shopping.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dead Neighbour</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/misc/my-dead-neighbour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/misc/my-dead-neighbour/</guid>
      <description>Living in a big city sometimes means you don&amp;rsquo;t get to know your neighbours and your community as good as you would in a small town, which may or may not be a bad thing. I once lived in a place on the 40th floor of a forty-something-storey building where there were 8 flats on each floor. Having a soul-sucking office job at the time that required long hours, I was at home for so little that I had never met my neighbours even once.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
