<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:14:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gang Leader</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</guid>
      <description>“By some account, he was the richest person in the country.” The line came from the obituary of Super Man (Man was his last name), the gang leader who once terrorised the populace of the Republic of Slofland, and who later ripped money off the same populace. Towards the end of his life, he became wealthy and, as a result of his wealth, respectable.
When his mother read that line, she smiled with pride, as if the mere fact that her son was rich were more than enough to compensate for the fact that her son was dead before she became a corpse herself: he was only thirty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the umbrella</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/under-the-umbrella/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/under-the-umbrella/</guid>
      <description>I. Memory and cognition  “The struggle of man against power is the struggle of memory against forgetting”—Milan Kundera
 I will always admit that I have a memory far better than I like, in a sense that I remember things so well that sometimes it hurts. But no matter how well someone or something was once etched onto the slate, time made those markings fade, either because something new was etched on it, or the markings became shallower after years and years of exposed in the elements, and some of them will eventually become invisible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>