<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Crime on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Crime/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Crime on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Crime/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to blow up the world</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/how-to-take-revenge-on-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/how-to-take-revenge-on-the-world/</guid>
      <description>Florian sat at his place in the open-planned office, staring at the grey screen, with colourful codes standing out against the dark screen. He was asked to fix a stupid bug in the operating system his employer sold to millions. Fixing bugs had ben his only job for a few years now.
This is so fucking boring. This job is just a glorified fire-fighter. In fact, even fire-fighter&amp;rsquo;s job is more glorious than mine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gang Leader</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</guid>
      <description>“By some account, he was the richest person in the country.” The line came from the obituary of Super Man (Man was his last name), the gang leader who once terrorised the populace of the Republic of Slofland, and who later ripped money off the same populace. Towards the end of his life, he became wealthy and, as a result of his wealth, respectable.
When his mother read that line, she smiled with pride, as if the mere fact that her son was rich were more than enough to compensate for the fact that her son was dead before she became a corpse herself: he was only thirty.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
