<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Non Fiction on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/non-fiction/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Non Fiction on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 04:03:04 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Second-Hand Time</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/second-hand-time-svetlana-alexievich/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 04:03:04 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/second-hand-time-svetlana-alexievich/</guid>
      <description>It would have been a strange situation to find yourself in, that the ideas you&amp;rsquo;d grown up with turned out to be out-of-fashion, and that what you&amp;rsquo;d been working for your whole life turned out to be worthless. It happens every so often to some people, but rarely at the scale of a whole country.
In her latest work, Svetlana Alexievich, the winner of Nobel Prize in 2015, tackles exactly this strange phenomenon during the collapse and the aftermath of the collapse of the Soviet Union.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Voices from Chernobyl: The Oral History of a Nuclear Disaster</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/voices-from-chernobyl-svetlana-alexievich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 16:34:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/bookshelf/voices-from-chernobyl-svetlana-alexievich/</guid>
      <description>Some years ago, I went through a phase of watching every documentary film I could get my hands on. One of the films I stumbled upon was a film about the Chernobyl disaster. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t remember when I first watched it, and it might not have anything to do with the Fukushima disaster. As with so many of the things I find interesting, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t any inherent reason why I found the Chernobyl disaster fascinating.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>