<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sonnet on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Sonnet/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sonnet on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 05:48:23 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Sonnet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sorrow in the Dark</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/sorrow-in-the-dark/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 05:48:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/sorrow-in-the-dark/</guid>
      <description>The night is always when the sorrow grows: The world is silent, everyone&amp;rsquo;s asleep. I sit alone and let my sadness flows, My eyes run dry despite my urge to weep.
Your kindness gives me courage to survive, Your caring touches me and warms my heart. But all your words and words cannot revive The sense of life that has been ripped apart.
The lights of city mask the twinkling stars, But what would I feel if the stars were seen?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I waited for your call</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-waited-for-your-call/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 16:05:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-waited-for-your-call/</guid>
      <description>I watched my phone and waited for your call But never heard from you nor seen your trace. The endless waiting made my anguish tall, My heart was pumping fast like running race.
The wine had not my poor nerve calmed the least, The music roused my soul with bitter rage. I closed my eyes and wished my pain decreased, The storm in me was trapped within a cage.
My tears were falling through the stale sad air, Your face appeared inside my drunken mind: A face which meant beyond just sweet and fair, But a heart more than just gentle and kind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I think about you to dream of you</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-think-about-you-to-dream-of-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 18:44:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/i-think-about-you-to-dream-of-you/</guid>
      <description>They used to say: &amp;ldquo;you dream of what you think.&amp;rdquo; So I thought about you to dream of you, I poured a glass of bitter wine to drink Myself to sleep the sleep and dream of you.
But then I looked and searched and found you not, Instead I heard her voice and saw her face. She said her love for me had yet to rot, But in truth, it&amp;rsquo;s long gone to outer space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We were all once young and dumb</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/we-were-all-once-young-and-dumb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 16:52:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/we-were-all-once-young-and-dumb/</guid>
      <description>I sat and thought about the distant past When we were all once young and very dumb. I gave you up for love which hardly last: The love which broke my heart; regrets to come.
I needed you to heal my wounded soul, But you were hurt as much and left the place. I looked for you with my heart hardly whole, With tears flow like little streams on my face.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I was the lone passenger, until…</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/lone-passenger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/poetry/lone-passenger/</guid>
      <description>Alone on a quiet, frozen train, I rode With no one but the sound of speeding wheels. Approaching the next station, the train slowed. There, she announced her entrance with her heels.
I turned towards the new presence, who sat With her face towards me. She was alone. She smiled at me. My heart shuddered at that, For she was both a known and an unknown —
She had to be a twin sister of yours Whom you had never known.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
