<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Adultery on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Adultery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Adultery on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 03:36:20 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Adultery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>What you feel when you kill yourself</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/what-you-feel-when-you-kill-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 03:36:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/what-you-feel-when-you-kill-yourself/</guid>
      <description>I always wonder what you felt when you were in the process of killing yourself.
I sometimes picture myself jumping off a high building, stabbing myself in the heart, or taking a crazy amount of painkillers and strong alcohol together. When earth&amp;rsquo;s gravity pulls me down at 10ms-2, what will I feel when the wind came rushing towards my face? What will I feel when I hit the ground? How painful will that be?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wrong Affair</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/wrong-affair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 09:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/wrong-affair/</guid>
      <description>The temperature was well above 34 degree centigrade under the summer sun. With tall buildings trapping the air, hundreds of people jamming into narrow pavements, and cars blowing out hot and toxic exhaust gasses, the streets at the heart of Hong Kong was a bamboo steamer in dim sum restaurants. Elizabeth Leung was wearing a white, short-sleeve top, but she regretted not wearing a skirt, which would allow some occasional breezes for her legs; not there those breezes would be cool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
