<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Github on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/Github/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Github on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 15:07:55 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/Github/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>From Github Pages to Firebase, then to a VPS</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/switching-from-github-pages-to-firebase/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2016 15:07:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/switching-from-github-pages-to-firebase/</guid>
      <description>Ever since I went static, I have been using Github Pages, an almost perfect solution for small static sites.
The only real shortcoming of Github Pages is the lack of control over the webserver, and hence the lack of control over caching and server-side redirect. While using Cloudflare does give you back some control, redirect capability remains lacking.
A few weeks ago, I moved the site to Firebase, which was a step up from Github Pages in terms of its flexibility, though I remained somewhat dissatisfied for various minor annoyances.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I deploy my Hugo site to my webserver</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-site-deployment-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 16:42:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/hugo-site-deployment-workflow/</guid>
      <description>This post has been updated to reflect my new deployment process after migrating to Firebase This post has been updated to reflect further important changes
Static site generators are great&amp;mdash;Jekyll is great, and Hugo is even greater&amp;mdash;except when it comes to updating the website. In the old days of my using wordpress, updating a post was a matter of logging in to the Wordpress Admin, making changes to the post, and hitting the &amp;ldquo;save&amp;rdquo; button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to create a super-fast Jekyll site</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/performant-jekyll-site-with-gulp-cloudflare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 14:23:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/performant-jekyll-site-with-gulp-cloudflare/</guid>
      <description>(Update: this site now runs on Hugo)
Earlier, I wrote a brief note explaining why I use Jekyll, which came down to two major factors: cost and performance. Hosting a Jekyll site on Github is free, eliminating all the costs (save the domain name) associated with running a self-hosted Wordpress site; and Github Pages is very fast.
But there are still some room for improvments. The steps outlined below are what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to optimise my website, partly inspired by David Ensinger&amp;rsquo;s post on the same topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jekyll: a static site generator</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/tech/jekyll/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 11:27:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/tech/jekyll/</guid>
      <description>(Update: this site now runs on Hugo)
For a long time, Wordpress was my go-to software to create website. It is free, has a huge community, massive collection of plugins, is not too difficult to set up for basic use, and is capable of running big and complex website. I used Wordpress to run a fairly large and complicated site for quite a while, and it did the job.
But when it came to this particular website, I had one problem.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
