<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Music on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Music on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 13:37:22 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>On Herbert von Karajan</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/herbert-von-karajan-musicianship/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 13:37:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/herbert-von-karajan-musicianship/</guid>
      <description>One of the great conductors whom I idolised in my teens was Herbert von Karajan, an Austrian conductor who was the chief conductor of the Berliner Philharmoniker for more than thirty years. The first video recording of an orchestra that I saw was Karajan&amp;rsquo;s conducting Beethoven sixth and seventh symphonies on laser disc, which fascinated me with an incredible visual imagery of the orchestra. One of my music teachers at the time also revered Herbert von Karajan, saying that he was amazed by how much power he could get from the orchestra with minimal gestures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case Against Audiophile</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/the-case-against-audiophile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 16:13:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/the-case-against-audiophile/</guid>
      <description>As a lifelong listener of classical music, and orchestral music and operas in particular, the importance of having a decent audio system has become known to me for as long as I have been listening to music. When I was small, I used to play compact discs (CDs) recordings on a small audio system, which, as one would expect, did no justice to the recordings. Later, I convinced my parents to upgrade the audio system at home to a beginner&amp;rsquo;s level high-fidelity system, with an integrated amplifier and a pair of bookshelf-style speakers, which, of course, probably weren&amp;rsquo;t very good, but I was able to enjoy it for some years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Franz Schubert: Grand Duo, D 812</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/music/schubert-grand-duo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2016 11:39:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/music/schubert-grand-duo/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operas and Their Absurd Stories</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-operas-and-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 06:46:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-operas-and-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>Natalie Dessay, a French soprano, once said that text of many operas are silly. She wasn&amp;rsquo;t the first to say it, and she won&amp;rsquo;t be the last.
Mozart&amp;rsquo;s Die Zauberflöte, the libretto of which was written by Emmanuel Schikaneder, is a great first-time opera: it has tuneful melodies, humours, and relatively easy story. But when you strip away the Masonic theme, Die Zauberflöte is a love story that makes no sense: Tamino falls in love with Pamina because he sees her picture, and Pamina falls in love with Tamino because she hears that Tamino falls in love with her after seeing her picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>La Soledad</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/music/la-soledad/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2016 17:49:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/music/la-soledad/</guid>
      <description>You came to me as poetry comes in song
and you showed me a new world of passion.
You loved me without conditions or reason
while I ignorant of the meaning of love protected my heart.
The sun has gone and now I sing of you
this solitude consumes me.
Forgive me if I was stolen away by fear.
You came to me I did not know how to love</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peter I. Tchaikovsky: Souvenir de Florence</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/music/tchaikovsky-souvenir-de-florence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 17:40:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/music/tchaikovsky-souvenir-de-florence/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gustav Mahler: Piano Quartet</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/music/mahler-piano-quartet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 17:34:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/music/mahler-piano-quartet/</guid>
      <description>With the second movement completed by Alfred Schnittke.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On musical structure and storytelling</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-musical-structure-and-storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2016 11:30:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-musical-structure-and-storytelling/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve spent much of my early life trying to be a classical musician&amp;mdash;a pianist, or a conductor, perhaps&amp;mdash;before spending a lot of time thinking of becoming a writer and actually doing something about it. So it may sound strange to you, but I often think of fiction in musical terms. A novel is a symphony, while a short story is a short piano piece by Chopin.
As someone who loves orchestral music more than piano music, let me say from the outset that I&amp;rsquo;m not fond of Chopin&amp;rsquo;s music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On happy endings</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-happy-endings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 03:28:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/on-happy-endings/</guid>
      <description>Christian Thielemann, one of the best, if not the best, conductors of the works of Wagner alive, once noted that none of the Wagner operas end in minor keys. Indeed, not even the apocalyptic ending of Götterdämmerung, the fourth and the final installment of the epic cycle Der Ring des Nibelungen, where the world ends with Brünnhilde jumping into the fire and the gods dies, ends in a minor key: Der Ring des Nibelungen starts with Das Rheingold in E-flat major and ends with Götterdämmerung in D-flat major.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Franz Schubert: Winterreise</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/music/schubert-winterreise/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2015 17:18:07 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/music/schubert-winterreise/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Forgotten Music</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/forgotten-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/forgotten-music/</guid>
      <description>A few months ago, when I was tidying up my study, I flipped open the score of Chopin’s Mazurkas, and I discovered that the pages for one of the Mazurkas was filled with pencil markings, a clear indication that I had learned that piece at one point, yet I couldn’t remember having learned it at all. I took it to the piano, and as I played it for the first time in decades, my fingers seemed to run on the keyboard on their own to the right directions and hit the right keys, an indisputable proof that I had learned the piece at some point.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>