<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hong Kong on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/hong-kong/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hong Kong on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:17:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/hong-kong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Dead Neighbour</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/misc/my-dead-neighbour/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 16:17:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/misc/my-dead-neighbour/</guid>
      <description>Living in a big city sometimes means you don&amp;rsquo;t get to know your neighbours and your community as good as you would in a small town, which may or may not be a bad thing. I once lived in a place on the 40th floor of a forty-something-storey building where there were 8 flats on each floor. Having a soul-sucking office job at the time that required long hours, I was at home for so little that I had never met my neighbours even once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Wrong Affair</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/wrong-affair/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2016 09:44:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/wrong-affair/</guid>
      <description>The temperature was well above 34 degree centigrade under the summer sun. With tall buildings trapping the air, hundreds of people jamming into narrow pavements, and cars blowing out hot and toxic exhaust gasses, the streets at the heart of Hong Kong was a bamboo steamer in dim sum restaurants. Elizabeth Leung was wearing a white, short-sleeve top, but she regretted not wearing a skirt, which would allow some occasional breezes for her legs; not there those breezes would be cool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Under the umbrella</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/essays/under-the-umbrella/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/essays/under-the-umbrella/</guid>
      <description>I. Memory and cognition  “The struggle of man against power is the struggle of memory against forgetting”—Milan Kundera
 I will always admit that I have a memory far better than I like, in a sense that I remember things so well that sometimes it hurts. But no matter how well someone or something was once etched onto the slate, time made those markings fade, either because something new was etched on it, or the markings became shallower after years and years of exposed in the elements, and some of them will eventually become invisible.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>