<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dystopia on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</title>
    <link>https://novelist.xyz/tag/dystopia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dystopia on Peter Y. Chuang - Novelist, Short Story Writer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:14:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://novelist.xyz/tag/dystopia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gang Leader</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 17:14:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-gang-leader/</guid>
      <description>“By some account, he was the richest person in the country.” The line came from the obituary of Super Man (Man was his last name), the gang leader who once terrorised the populace of the Republic of Slofland, and who later ripped money off the same populace. Towards the end of his life, he became wealthy and, as a result of his wealth, respectable.
When his mother read that line, she smiled with pride, as if the mere fact that her son was rich were more than enough to compensate for the fact that her son was dead before she became a corpse herself: he was only thirty.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Last Living Soul</title>
      <link>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-last-living-soul/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://novelist.xyz/short-stories/the-last-living-soul/</guid>
      <description>I knew. For a long time, I knew I was in part a creation of someone called the scientist. Since the scientist was responsible for the existence of me and others of my own type, a few of us regarded the scientist with a god-like reverence, while others held him/her in utter contempt. No one knew him/her: there was no photograph, painted portrait, nor busts of the scientist, and we had no idea regarding his/her name, and whether this person was a man or woman.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>